(改编自加斯瑞斯克哈尔伯格的小说)
焰火之城
第一季第三集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
小萨一直都在这里 没有谁比她更爱音乐了
Sam was here all the time. No one loves the music like her.
对于小萨来说 音乐就是信仰
For Sam, it's a religion.
无论有多拥挤 她总能想办法到最前面
Doesn't matter how crowded it is, she always finds her way to the front.
她从不错过任何一场演出 每晚的演出都更精彩
She never missed a show. Every night was better than the last.
4号那天晚上 有一支乐队在这里表演 他们名叫从无到有
The night of the 4th, a band was playing here, called Ex Nihilo.
你见到萨曼莎了吗
You see Samantha?
是的 但是她没留下来看演出 这很不像她
Yeah, but she didn't stay for the show, which was unlike her.
一定是有其他重要的事
Must've had somewhere real important to be.
她说要去上城 但是会回来
Said she was going uptown, but she'd be back.
但我没有再见过她 她还好吗
But I didn't see her again. Is she okay?
萨曼莎来的时候是一个人吗
Was Samantha alone when she came by?
和一个小伙子一起
With a young dude.
他进去了 不确定他什么时候离开的
He went inside. Not sure when he left.
穿28号的牛仔裤  可能会小便失禁的那种男生吗
Size 28 jeans? Type of guy who might piss himself?
听起来是的
Sounds about right.
你能向人像画师形容他的样子吗
You think you can describe him to a sketch artist?
你肯定养成了记人脸的习惯
Bet you make it a habit to remember faces.
但我不习惯告诉警察
But not talk to cops.
来警局吧 别人不需要知道
Come by the station. No one has to know.
嘿 查理 你醒了
Hey, Charlie. You're awake.
你是说有意识了
You mean conscious?
在被你的男友击昏后
After being knocked unconscious by your boyfriend?
好吧 索尔没有用很大力
Okay, Sol didn't hit you that hard.
相信我 我觉得你只是累了
Trust me. Think you were mostly tired.
我的手机和钱包也不见了
I'm also missing my cell phone and my wallet.
我被绑架了吗
Have I been kidnapped?
好 听着 如果扣押我是为索取赎金
Okay, look. If you're holding me for ransom,
我的妈妈可没钱
my mom doesn't have any money.
可不是 你看起来并不是“高价值目标”
Yeah, no shit. You don't exactly scream "high-value target."
我们只是想问问你昨晚看到了些什么
We just have some questions about what you saw last night.
我什么都没看到
I didn't see anything.
我们知道这不是真的
We know that's not true.
那...我的意思是 我见到的东西 我...
Well-- What I meant was, what-- What I did see, I'm--
我并不明白那是什么 而且我很愿意把它抛到脑后
I didn't understand, and I'm more than willing to forget it.
是吗 那你为什么一开始 就在那里鬼鬼祟祟的
No? Why were you creeping around in the first place?
你可以把那玩意放下了
And you can drop that right fucking now.
在我把它从你的小鸡爪子里 抢过来再插进你屁股之前
Before I rip it from your bony hands and shove it up your ass.
我...但是我不是鬼鬼祟祟 我是来找人帮忙的
I-- But I wasn't creeping. I came for help.
帮什么忙
What kind of help?
小萨出事了 听说了吗
Did you guys hear about Sam?
我们的小萨
Our Sam?
一个女孩在中央公园被枪击
A girl got shot in Central Park.
什么
What?
小萨中枪了
Sam got shot.
小萨没事吧
Is Sam okay?
是 她还活着
Yeah, she's alive.
她处于昏迷状态
She's in a coma.
但是 我去过公园 我找到她了
But I was there in the park, I found her.
该死 查理哥们
Damn, Charlie man.
你还看到什么了吗
Did you see anything else?
有
Yeah.
那里有个男的站在她旁边
There was this guy standing over her.
他看起来很难过 但...
He seemed upset, but--
但更像是他发现了她 而不是伤害了她
but maybe more like he found her than he hurt her.
我不清楚
I don't know.
我听到警车的声音就跑了 但...
I heard police sirens and then I ran, but...
那里有...
There was a...
她的脑门有个孔
a hole in her forehead.
那里到处是血
There was blood everywhere.
如果我按时赶到 你知道 要是我...
I mean, if I'd been on time, you know, if only I'd--
可是我却在跳舞 偷喝酒 还嗑嗨了
Instead I was dancing, and stealing drinks and getting high.
但我只是想有好玩的故事 可以讲给她听
But I just wanted a good story to tell her, you know.
她爱听有趣的故事
She loves a good story.
你为什么来这里
Why did you come here?
我不知道还能去哪
I mean, I didn't know where else to go.
但是 你们认识小萨
But, I mean, you guys know Sam.
对吗
Right?
也许你们知道为什么 她原计划和我们一起玩 却离开了
You might know why she made plans to hang out and then just took off?
她为什么把我留在夜店
Why she left me at that club
然后去了一个我们从没 去过的地方 还被枪击了
and then went somewhere we'd never gone before and got shot?
拜托了 你们一定要帮我
Please, you guys have to help me.
我没有别的人可问了 我的...妈妈 她只会将我永久禁足
I-I have no one else. My-- My mom, she'll just ground me forever.
我的心理医生只会告诉我 说我试图救小萨
My therapist will just tell me that I'm trying to save Sam
因为我当初无法救我爸爸 或别的...
because I couldn't save my dad, or some--
你爸爸怎么了
What happened to your dad?
他...
He...
他死在了北塔
He died in North Tower.
天
Oh, fuck.
查理哥们
Charlie man?
你来对地方了 我们会查清楚的
You came to the right place. We're gonna figure this out.
(剧场)
我不敢相信我被你说服了
I can't believe I let you talk me into this.
是布鲁诺 你爱布鲁诺啊
It's Bruno. You love Bruno.
布鲁诺爱布鲁诺 他是我的艺廊经营者
Bruno loves Bruno. He's my gallerist.
他只在乎一件事 那就是他能卖出去的艺术品
He only cares about one thing and that is art he can sell.
他还带了珍妮来
And he brought Jenny.
艺廊女生是最糟的
Gallery girls are the fucking worst.
她们会讨好你 告诉你你是天才
How they fawn over you and tell you you're a genius.
那真糟糕啊
That's terrible.
- 嗨 你好吗  - 嗨
- Hi. How are you? - Hi.
- 这发型啊 - 别说啦
- This hair, though! - Stop it.
是你自己弄的
Did you do that yourself,
- 还是找人弄的呀  - 拜托
- or did you bring somebody over? - Please.
- 绝对是专业人士 - 专业人士
- Professional all the way. - Professional.
你想知道威廉的问题在哪里吗
You wanna know the problem with William?
我给你解释 墨瑟 好吗
I'll explain it to you, Mercer. Okay?
拜托 他很清楚我的缺点
Please. He's very familiar with my flaws.
他太有天赋了
He was too naturally talented.
那...真可悲
That's-- How tragic.
- 别说了 - 很可怕 真的
- Stop. - It's awful. Really.
不 我认真的 好吗
No. It's true. Okay?
他拥有一切 轻而易举 对吗
Everything has happened for him. Without any effort, right?
含着金汤匙出生 这辈子从不需要工作一天
Born to great wealth. Never needed to work a day in his life.
所以当他遇到困难 他视其为失败
So when he struggles, he views this as a failure,
而不是过程的一部分 懂吧
instead of part of the process. You see?
行 搞心理治疗呢
Okay, therapy.
你不能怪他
You can't blame him.
他的乐队出了一张专辑 那专辑帮助定义了一代人
His band made one album, it helped define a generation.
然后他放弃音乐 转向绘画
Then he gives up music to paint,
他的首场展览就上了《艺术论坛》的封面
and his first show gets the cover of Art Forum.
对 从迈阿密到北京 每一位收藏家
Yes, and every collector from Miami to Beijing
都在争抢他的作品
is fighting over his pieces.
不过只有一个小问题
Except, there's only one little problem--
要开始了 来了
Here we go. It's coming.
他们等待 但是再也没有作品了
They wait, but then there's no more art.
要来了 作品要来了
It's coming, the art is coming.
- 我只需要再多几个月... - 你总是这么对我说
- I just need a few more months-- - This is what you always say to me,
所以我也这么和买家说
and so this is what I tell the buyers.
但你知道吗 没有作品 在他们看来 我就成了骗子
But you know what? When there's nothing, they look at me like I'm a liar.
- 这 我... - 其实
- Well, I-- - Actually,
通常是我和客户打电话联络
I'm usually the one on the phone dealing with the clients.
你一定有什么可以展示给他们
You must have something you're ready to show them.
他所有时间都花在工作室里 他每天好几个小时都在里面
He spends all of his time in the studio. He's there every day for hours?
我手头是有创作中的作品 对
There are some things that I am working on, yes.
有想法 其实更像是...概念
There are ideas. They're more like-- More of concepts, really.
我非常想看到它们实现潜力
I am very excited for them to reach their potential.
但是正如我说的 我需要更多时间
But, as I've said, I need a little more time.
不 听着 没有时间了 好吗
No. Look, there is no more time, okay?
拜托了 威廉 已经有人开始问 你是不是死了
Please. William, people are starting to ask me if you died.
真是个混蛋 嘿 累积需求越多越好 对吧
What a bastard. Hey! The more pent-up demand is, right?
- 这样价格越高 - 拜托 他只是在谦虚
- The higher the price is. - Come on. He's just being modest.
他从不认为自己的作品出色
He never thinks anything he does is any good.
好吧 这交给我们评判
Okay, well, we will be the judge of that.
本
Ben.
- 那是什么意思 你在做什么  - 什么 我们走了
- What does that mean? What are you doing? - What? We're leaving.
- 我们去哪里  - 我们去工作室
- Where are we going? - We're going to the studio.
我们都得看看你在创作些什么
We all must see what it is that you have been creating.
不过我先喝杯浓缩咖啡
I'm gonna get an espresso first, though.
听着 大家来这里是因为我们都支持你
Look, everyone is here because we are rooting for you.
好吗 我们爱你 威廉
All right? We love you, William.
- 还需要什么吗  - 不
- Would you like anything else? - No.
- 动身 走吧 - 走 去叫辆德士
- Come on. Let's go. - Go, get a cab.
我们外面见 好吗 我去洗手间
I'll meet you outside, okay? I'm gonna hit the head.
好的
Okay.
我妈有夜惊的毛病 会做梦梦见我死去
My mom has night terrors. Like, dreams where I die.
所以她就连让我去上学 都要挣扎一番 你知道吗
So it's hard for her to even let me go to school, you know?
所以她讨厌小萨
Which means she hated Sam.
因为小萨将我拉进那个世界
'Cause Sam pulled me into the world.
拉进了她的世界 而那个世界嘛 不太安全
Into Sam's world, which is not exactly risk-free.
所以发生的事可以说是 拉蒙娜威斯巴格最坏的噩梦了
So what happened was basically Ramona Weisbarger's worst nightmare,
只不过是发生在小萨身上
except it happened to Sam.
而我也有责任
No thanks to me.
你真以为自己能够保护她
You really think you could have protected her?
- 扳倒一个带枪的家伙  - 不...我...
- Taken down a guy with a gun? - No. I--
但如果我在场 我愿意为她挡下子弹
But I would have taken a bullet for her if I was there.
自责
Guilt.
解释了你为什么带着这个
Explains why you've been carrying this around.
(钦定版圣经)
先知查理
Charlie, the Prophet.
不是的 我读都没读过
No. I haven't even read it.
我都不确定如果读了我是否会相信 但...
I'm not sure if I'd even believe it if I did. But...
我猜里面有关于宽恕的话
presumably, there's something about forgiveness in there.
你现在需要那个吗
That's what you need right now?
非常需要 我甚至无法呼吸
So bad I can hardly breathe.
查理 好的 闭上眼睛
Oh, Charlie. Okay, close your eyes.
想着萨曼莎 让她充满你的思绪
You think of Samantha. Let the thought of her fill you up.
现在睁开眼睛
Now, open your eyes.
看着我 直直看着我 别移开目光
Look at me. Right at me. Don't look away.
《圣经》说所有真正忏悔的罪孽者
The Bible says that all sinners who truly repent,
应被施以极大的慈悲 被宽恕所有的罪行
shall be granted great mercy and forgiven all offenses.
无论我们做了什么或为什么做
Doesn't matter what we've done, or why we did it.
这是上帝的律法
This is the law of God.
当然 我不是牧师
Now, I'm no priest.
不过是一个有在主日学校好好听课的小孩
Just a kid who paid attention in Sunday school.
但这里就我们两个男人
But I am the only other guy here,
意味着赦罪的职责只能落在我肩上
which means the job of absolution falls on me.
查理威斯巴格 我赦免你的罪
Charlie Weisbarger, I absolve you.
你已被赦免
You are absolved.
嘿 小子 发生在小萨身上的事 并不是你的错 听到了吗
Hey, kid, what happened to Sam is not your fault. You hear me?
说出来
Say it.
- 发生在小萨身上的事不是我的错 - 不 要真的相信
- What happened to Sam was not my fault. - Nah, a little more like you mean it.
发生在小萨身上的事不是我的错
What happened to Sam was not my fault.
站起来 喊出来
You stand up and yell it.
- 发生在小萨身上的事不是我的错 - 喊出来
- What happened to Sam was not my fault. - Yell it.
- 发生在小萨身上的事不是我的错 - 大声
- What happened to Sam was not my fault. - Louder!
发生在小萨身上的事不是我的错
What happened to Sam was not my fault!
显然 它还处在理论阶段
Obviously, it's living in a theoretical space.
(点)
它变得更具体有形的生命之旅刚开始
Just beginning its life journey into a more tangible form.
所以这是个停车标志
So that's a stop sign?
曾经是停车标志 现在是“点”标志
I mean, it was a stop sign, but now it is a "spot" sign.
拜托 哟 就...
Come on. Yo, just--
想象一下 在纽约街头遇到这个
Imagine encountering this in the streets of New York City.
对 因为街道是唯一一个
Yes, because the streets is the only place
人们会见到这种垃圾的地方
where anyone is going to see this piece of shit.
威廉 你还有别的作品吗
Do you have anything else, William?
没有已经完成到这一步的
I mean, nothing that is as far along as this.
没有比“点”标志更完整的作品  我不懂了 威廉
Far along as a "spot" sign? I don't understand, William.
你总是泡在这里
After all the time you've been spending here,
这就是你唯一能交出来的东西
this is all you have to show for it?
拜托 墨瑟 别说了 好吗
Please. Mercer, please. Okay?
他显然只是来这里吸毒
It is obvious he has been coming here only to get high.
而且你现在已经嗑嗨了 对吧
Not to mention that you are high right now, huh?
对 你瞧 你浪费了我的时间
Yeah. See? You have wasted my time.
但是更糟的是你浪费了自己的才华
But worse, you are wasting your talent.
有争议 但我挺喜欢的
Controversial, but I kind of love it.
所以你在剧场餐厅的洗手间注射毒品了
So, you shot up in the bathroom at Odeon?
我又没办法在桌子上弄
It's not like I could've just done it right there at the table.
麦克纳利对那种行为不待见
McNally sort of frowns at that.
- 你说过要戒的 - 我会戒的
- You said you were quitting. - I will.
我在戒 好吗 宝贝 我真的想戒 我会的
I am, okay? Babe. I really want to. I'm going to.
我想要的是不再为了这件事争吵
What I want is to stop having this fight.
我们这样要怎么走下去
How are we supposed to go on like this?
也许我们不该走下去
Maybe we're not supposed to.
你在走一条黑暗的道路 威廉
You're going down a dark road, William.
尽头是一个“点”标志
One that ends in a "spot" sign
除此之外什么都没了
and nothing else.
蕾根 我们不知道你会来 亲爱的
Regan, we weren't expecting you, dear.
尝尝鸡蛋 口感像云一样很松软
Try the eggs. It's like eating a cloud.
不 我不会留下
No, I'm not staying.
我来这里只是因为我觉得让爸爸和我
I'm just here because I thought it might be nice for Daddy and I
一起走进办公室比较好
to walk into the office together.
这对他来说会是艰难的一天
It's gonna be a rough day for him,
因为有人把审前传讯泄露给媒体了
since someone leaked the pretrial arraignment to the press.
(汉密尔顿斯维尼集团老板 因欺诈指控被起诉)
我看到了 真是卑鄙
I saw. Nasty stuff.
我还以为我们人缘很好
And I thought people liked us.
人们喜欢丑闻 无论谁受损
People like scandal at anyone's expense.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
嗨 爸爸 你没穿好衣服
Hi, Daddy. You're not dressed.
艾莫里和菲莉希亚没告诉你
Amory and Felicia didn't tell you?
我今天不去上班 或者说 以后也不去
I'm not going in today. Or ever.
没人告诉过我啊
This is the first I'm hearing of it.
我的错 这是他审前释放的条件之一
My failing. It's a condition of his pretrial release.
不 我读过协议 上面根本没提到
No, I read the agreement and it said nothing about him
他不去办公室
not going into the office.
是在附件备忘录里写的 以防协议被泄露
It was in a side memo in case the agreement was leaked,
也的确被泄露了 那帮秃鹰
as it was, the fucking vultures.
就当是退休吧 我已经开始策划派对了
We'll call it retirement. I've already started planning the party.
派对
A party.
唯一比你父亲的辩护更重要的是他的健康
The only thing more important than your father's defense is his health.
这样他可以同时关注于两件事
This way, he can focus on both.
律师可以来这里办事 一切都是私下处理 舒舒服服
The lawyers can come here to work. Everything very private, comfortable.
爸 这是你想要的吗
Dad, is that what you want?
亲爱的 这是大家想要的
Darling, it's what everyone wants.
你努力工作 创造美好的人生 然后终于能享受了
You work hard to create a beautiful life, then you finally get to enjoy it.
要我说 越早享受越好
The sooner the better, I say.
亲爱的 你去 照常工作
You go, sweetie. Business as usual.
董事会得看到你可以处理好事务 在没有我的情况下
The board needs to see that you can handle things. Without me.
我会打电话给你的 我爱你
Well, I'll call you. I love you.
我也爱你
Love you too.
如果你不给我她的号码 请直接打给她 这事很重要
If you won't give me her number, please just call her, it's important.
- 再说一次 我叫墨... - 墨瑟
- Once again my name is M-- - Mercer.
抱歉 兰普莱特太太 我不知道你认识他
Sorry, Mrs. Lamplighter. I didn't realize that you knew him.
真的吗 为什么
Oh, really? And why is that?
嘿 我可投票给了丁肯斯
Hey. I voted for Dinkins.
好吧
Okay.
我只是来看我父亲 你为什么来这
I was just stopping by to see my father. What are you doing here?
我只知道在这个地方能找到你 这事不能等 是关于威廉
It was the only place I knew to find you. It couldn't wait. It's William.
我们今晚会在我们的公寓组织戒毒干预会
We're having an intervention at our apartment tonight.
不 他会很不喜欢的
No. He's gonna hate that.
他更不喜欢的是死
Not as much as he'll hate being dead.
已经那么严重了
It's that bad?
我知道他想要帮助
I know he wants help.
即使他不开口要求
Even if he won't ask for it.
所以我承担下责任 去找任何还在乎威廉的
So I've just been tasked with finding any of William's friends and family
朋友和家人
who still care about him.
- 是 - 希望这包括你
- Yeah. - I hope that includes you.
(前事追溯 《黄铜战术》)
小萨是一位艺术家
Sam is an artist.
把这里用作她的工作室 也可能是储藏间
Used this place as her studio, or maybe a storage locker,
但是 我不知道这有什么重要的
but not sure how any of this matters.
我的直觉是小萨认识开枪的人
My instinct is Sam knew her shooter.
感觉这不是意外
This doesn't feel like a "wrong place, wrong time" situation.
萨曼莎没有被袭击 没有物品被偷走
Samantha wasn't assaulted. Nothing was stolen.
第一枪打偏了 第二枪击中了她 但是没有要她的命
First shot went wide, second one got her, but didn't kill her.
那个枪击者没有留下来确认这一点
Fact that the shooter didn't stick around to verify, you know,
还好如此
very thankful for that,
但这让我觉得 这是私人恩怨 但是业余人士做的
but it makes me think that this was personal, but amateur.
有动机的枪手 但没什么经验
A shooter with a motive, but not a lot of experience.
不幸的是
Now, unfortunately,
本案的大部分物证都用不上
most of the physical evidence in this case is shit.
所以我们找到这凶手的途径就是动机
So, the way we find this perp is motive.
也就是说要尽可能了解关于你女儿的一切
That means learning everything we can about your daughter.
有孩子吗
Got any kids?
还没有 正在努力
Not yet. I'm working on it.
那你完全不懂我的心情
Then you've no goddamn clue.
他们一出生起 你就尽一切努力去保护他们
Moment they're born, you do everything you can to protect them,
然后却发生了这样的事
and then something like this happens.
杨先生
Look, Mr. Yeung.
这是你经历过最艰难的一件事
This is the hardest thing you're ever gonna go through.
每个人都需要依靠些什么来支撑自己
And everybody needs something to lean on.
来维持信念 对我来说 我相信的是一位父亲的爱
To believe in. For me, I believe in a father's love.
我相信你
I believe in you.
我们要找到对她做了这事的人 但没有你的帮助就做不到
We're gonna find who did this to her, but not without your help.
没有谁比你更了解萨曼莎
You know Samantha better than anyone.
那是她最喜欢的
That one's her favorite.
我听说音乐对于昏迷中的人来说有益
You know, I think I heard that music is good for people in comas.
让他们与现实保持联结
Keeps them connected.
你找到手机了吗
You find a cell phone?
没有 她有手机吗
No. Did she have one?
从没给我她的号码 但我见她用过几次手机
Never gave me her number, but I saw her on it a couple times.
这样啊 也许是某个 不希望我们知道她和谁交朋友的人
Could be someone who didn't want us to know who her friends were.
你会想看看这个的
You'll wanna see this.
她叫这个杂志
She calls it a zine.
总是在弄这个
Was always working on it.
总是去金考店打印
Heading over to Kinko's all hours, making copies.
如果你想了解我的女儿 那信息都在这里面
If you wanna know my daughter, it's in there.
那么 你为什么会在这里
So, how'd you end up down here?
应该是因为我喜欢过山车吧
I guess because I love roller coasters.
我妈妈在我16岁时去世
My mom died when I was 16.
没有爸爸 所以在那之后 我就从路易斯安那一路北上流浪了
No dad, so I just kind of drifted up north from Louisiana after that.
从孟菲斯 到纳什维尔 辛辛那提 清理旅店房间
Cleaned motel rooms from Memphis to Nashville to Cincinnati.
然后我听说俄亥俄桑达斯基的杉点游乐园
Then I heard about Cedar Point in Sandusky, Ohio.
我想一个有18个世界级过山车
Figured a place with 18 world-class roller coasters
和一个水上乐园的地方应该不会太糟
and a water park couldn't be all bad.
但我错了
But I was wrong.
我不知道你对清理旅店房间 有什么了解 查理
I don't know what you've heard about cleaning motel rooms, Charlie,
但是这是个低工资 高风险的职业
but it's a low-pay, high-risk profession.
只能在短时间内赚到钱
Math only goes your way for so long.
然后发生了什么
And then what happens?
然后就不赚钱了
Then it goes the other way.
所以
So...
这是他们叫你“下水道女孩”的原因
that's why they call you Sewer Girl?
因为你住在下水道或...
'Cause you were, like, living in the gutters or--
不是
No.
不 尼基说我困在 某种较低水平的意识层面上
No, Nicky says I'm stuck on a lower level of consciousness.
我仍然会因为可爱的动物照片而感动
I still get sentimental about cute animal pics
还有我的星座这类玩意
and my horoscope and shit.
他说等我成长后我可以选个新的名字
He says I can pick a new name once I evolve,
但我好像习惯这名字了
but I don't know, kinda used to it.
好的 抱歉 那么 尼基是怎么回事
Okay, sorry, wha-- So, what's the deal with Nicky?
我以为他是翻唱乐队的主唱
I thought he was, like, the lead singer in a cover band?
你不懂 查理
You don't get it, Charlie.
但你会懂的 乐队只是个幌子
But you will. The band is the cover.
跟我来
Come with me.
立刻
Now.
跟上
Come on.
好的 这是乐队的排练地点 但我们正在翻改
Okay. This is the band's rehearsal space, but we're converting it.
你不需要知道改成什么
To what, you don't need to know.
但这些设备都要搬到地下室
But all this equipment goes into the basement,
窗户得封上 地毯得移除
the window needs to be covered and the carpet has to go.
好多地毯
That's a lot of carpet.
那你最好马上开始干活
Then you better get started.
等等 我要一个人做吗
Wait, I'm doing this all by myself?
这是尼基的主意
Was this Nicky's idea?
这里发生的一切都是尼基的主意
Nothing happens here that isn't Nicky's idea.
嘿 是给我的吗
Hey. Is that for me?
这是什么和你一点也无关
It's none of your goddamn business is what it is.
(证据)
(乌托邦 破裂的混沌)
(假装不孤独)
他很笨拙 像只小狗 眼神无辜 面带微笑
He was awkward. Like a puppy. Sweet-eyed. Smiley.
也许有些雀斑
Maybe some freckles.
他的头发是卷的 白人男孩的卷发 拖把发型
And his hair was curly. White boy curly. A mop.
像这样吗
Like this?
就是他
That's him.
真准啊 那孩子就是只小奶狗
Nailed it. That kid's a fucking labradoodle.
等等 枪击 什么枪击
Wait. A shooting? What shooting?
就在派对外面 中央公园的女孩
The-- Right outside the party. The girl in Central Park.
可怜的孩子是纽约大学的学生
Poor thing was an NYU student.
墨瑟发现了她 把外套盖在她身上
Mercer found her and put his jacket over her.
那是...威廉的外套 因为是他借的
Well, it's like-- It was William's jacket, 'cause he borrowed it.
然后 当警察找到毒品
And then when the cops found the drugs,
墨瑟意识到威廉是个瘾君子
that's when Mercer realized that William's a fucking junkie.
那女孩 她还好吗
Is she okay, this girl?
你还知道关于她的其他信息吗
You know anything else about her?
她处于昏迷状态
I mean, she's in a coma.
他们不会公布其他信息
And they're not releasing any other information.
据说她是大一生 我不清楚
Apparently she's a freshman, I think. I don't know.
她是大一生
She's freshman.
有什么区别呢 对吧
What difference does it make, really, right?
你说得对 是啊 就是个悲剧
You're right. Yeah, it's tragic.
天啊 我好紧张 我太紧张了
Oh, my God. I'm so nervous. I am so fucking nervous.
我懂
I get it.
你好
Hello.
蕾根
Regan,
要召开紧急董事会会议 我们得在办公室开会
there's an emergency board meeting. We need to convene at the office.
- 今晚吗  - 恐怕如此 时间紧迫
- Tonight? - Afraid so. It's time-sensitive.
我不能去 重新安排时间吧
I can't. Just reschedule.
让吉斯看孩子没问题吧
Well, surely Keith can watch the children.
正如我们担心的
As we feared,
董事会非常担忧比尔面临的指控
the board is extremely concerned about the charges against Bill.
那就向他们保证他是无辜的
So then reassure them that he's innocent.
- 你能不能... - 我...
- Can you get--? - Well, I--
- 我显然一再保证了 但... - 孩子
- Obviously, I have, strenuously, but-- - Kids.
艾莫里 是威廉的事 他遇到麻烦了 我得去帮他
Amory, it's William. He's in trouble, and I need to be there.
威廉 我不知道你们有联系
William. I hadn't realized you'd connected.
很抱歉让你为难
I'm sorry to put you in this position
逼你在父亲和弟弟之间做选择
having to choose between your father and your brother,
但这是目前的现实
but this is where we are.
如果你需要 随时找我
I'm here if you need me.
再见 艾莫里
Goodbye, Amory.
如果我想说 我会的 好吧
If I wanted to share, I would. Okay.
亲爱的 你的最爱
My dear, your favorite.
- 三文鱼 - 好吧
- Salmon. - Okay.
天啊 我不能迟到 我得走了
Oh, my God. I cannot be late. I have to go.
但你会留下 妈妈 对吗
But you're staying. Right, Mom?
不 宝贝 对不起 我不能
No. Sweetie, I'm sorry. I can't.
我只是来给你们做晚餐的
I just came to make you dinner.
我们应该感谢妈妈做晚餐
Which we should thank her for.
我说了 凯特 放弃吧 他们不会复合的
I told you, Cate. Give it up. They're not getting back together.
- 嘿 我们又不知道 - 我们知道
- Hey, we don't know that. - Yeah, we do.
无论如何 没什么比家庭更重要的
Still, there's nothing more important than family.
好吗
Okay?
我爱你们俩
I love you both.
威尔 尝尝吧 拜托了
Will, just try it, please.
你今天看够了 欣赏得开心吗
You got an eyeful today. Like what you saw?
我没说不喜欢 我只是不懂
I didn't not like it. I just don't understand.
你是索尔的女友 对吧  所以你也和尼基在一起
You're Sol's girl, right? So, are you with Nicky too, or what?
我可没有你那种乡巴佬式的玻璃心 我不会为此道歉
I won't apologize for not conforming to your delicate suburban sensibilities.
一夫一妻只是父权制度资本主义的工具
Monogamy is just a tool of patriarchal capitalism.
听起来像是小萨会说的话
That sounds exactly like something that Sam would say,
我则会假装理解
and that I would, like, pretend to understand.
小萨是个笃信者
Sam is a believer.
笃信什么 随便和人上床
A believer in what, sleeping around?
要我说 小萨在守身
If you ask me, Sammy's saving herself.
为谁守身
For what?
谁知道 也许是你呢 查理哥们
Who knows? Could be you, Charlie man.
嘿 过来
Hey. Come over here.
我们开始这场革命时 就知道会有代价
When we started this revolution, we knew it would have a cost.
今晚 我们要致敬 一位正在为自己的生命而战的受伤战士
And tonight, we celebrate a wounded warrior fighting for her life.
敬小萨 今晚是献给她的
To Sam. Tonight's for her.
- 敬小萨 - 小萨
- To Sammy. - To Sam. - To Sammy. - Sam.
什么叫为了小萨 我们在做什么
What's for Sam? What are we doing?
我们都不认识这小子
We don't even know this fucking kid.
他以非常快的速度进入了我们的圈子
He has had a rather rapid ascent into our good graces,
但他给我们带来什么好处了吗
but what does he bring to the table, really?
小萨喜欢他
Sam likes him.
所以呢 她什么都没和他说 那我们为什么要说
Yeah? Well, she didn't tell him shit. So, why should we?
好的 无论小萨知道什么 我也想知道
All right, well, whatever Sam knew, I wanna know too.
把我打晕 将我锁起来 逼我做苦工
Knock me out. Lock me up. Force me into hard labor.
随便什么 我什么都行
Whatever. I'm all in.
该死
Oh, shit.
他什么都行
He's all in.
我们走着瞧吧
Guess we'll see about that.
零点即将到来
The zero hour is upon us.
我们玩点好玩的吧
Let's have some fun.
- 别紧张 威廉不会敲门的 - 好的
- Relax. William wouldn't knock. - Right.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hey.
- 真感谢你来 - 是
- Thank you so much for coming. - Uh-huh.
蕾根 这是维纳斯德尼龙
Regan, this is Venus De Nylon.
嗨 我是威廉的姐姐
Hi. I'm William's sister.
我不知道他有个姐姐
Didn't know he had a sister.
维纳斯曾是前事追溯的键盘手
Venus played keyboard for Ex Post Facto.
必须由我代表乐队来
Had to represent.
原乐队的人要不就是比比利的情况更严重
Everyone from the original band's either more fucked up than Billy,
要不就是恨他或是已经死了
hates him or is already dead.
我们还在世的人只能尽我们所能了
Well, we who are living will have to do everything that we can.
你好 嗨
Hello. Hi.
来
Come.
- 请坐 - 谢谢
- Have a seat. - Thanks.
嘿
Hey.
我只想说声谢谢你
I just wanted to say thank you
感谢你在威廉身边没人的时候 陪伴和支持他
for being there for William when no one else was.
当然
Of course.
大家都准备好了吗
So, everyone ready?
- 是 - 对
- Yes. - Yeah.
威廉随时可能走进来
Any moment now, William's gonna walk through that door,
他大概不会喜欢眼前的景象
and he is probably not gonna like what he sees.
因为你们是来这里告诉他你们爱他
Because you're here to tell him that you love him.
爱意味着要承担责任
Love makes people accountable.
(中央公园枪击案尚无嫌犯)
嗨 我是小萨 请留言
Hey, you've reached Sam. Please leave a message,
你也可以用怀旧的方式 打我的传呼机
or you can do it the old-fashioned way and page me.
语音信箱已满 无法接收任何讯息...
The mailbox is full and cannot accept any messages--
(西西亚罗意大利餐厅)
- 你好 - 嗨 桑托斯太太
- Hello. - Hey, Mrs. Santos.
希望我的电话不算太迟
I hope I haven't called too late.
嗨 威廉 我叫厄尔
Hello, William. My name's Earl.
今天这些善良的人们聚在这里
These good folks here gathered today
是因为他们担心你会死去
because they're afraid that you're gonna die.
你想坐下吗
Would you like to have a seat?
不 厄尔 我不坐下
No, Earl, I would not.
好吧 威廉 听我说 这是我的主意
Okay, listen. This was my idea, William.
你可以生我的气 但是最重要的是 你需要生自己的气
So you can be mad at me, but mostly, you need to be mad at yourself.
因为你的毒瘾正在削弱 你作为艺术家的作品
Because your addiction is diminishing your work as an artist,
但你的谎言则在削弱你的人格
but your lying, your lying is diminishing you as a person.
所以求求你 不要表现得 像是你不需要这次干预
So please, please don't act like you are better than this.
说完了吗
You're done?
厄尔只是在尽本职 我很感谢他
Earl here is just doing his job. And I appreciate that.
就算是布鲁诺 我也理解
Fuck. I mean, Bruno, I understand.
我没有作品给你售卖
I have nothing for you to sell,
因此 我对你来说没有价值
and therefore I am of no value to you.
但是你 宝贝
But you, babe.
你
You?
你真觉得这会有用
Did you really think this was gonna work?
他不认为这会有用
He didn't think this would work.
他只是没别的办法向你表达他爱你了
He's just running out of ways to show you that he loves you.
你是哪位啊
Who are you exactly?
请...别这样
Don't-- Please don't do that.
我可真佩服
I'm impressed.
嘿 小蕾
Hey, Reegs.
有多久了 15年了吧
What-- What has it been, 15 years, right?
对 差不多吧
Yeah. Give or take.
天啊
Wow.
我用了那么久时间找到你
That's how long it took me to find you.
真的
Really?
别这样 别离开 不
Don't do that. Don't go. No.
我很想你
I miss you.
- 我的天啊 - 不 我非常想你
- Oh, my God. - No, I miss you so much.
- 我现在不能做这件事 我做不到 - 我从没停止想念你
- I can't do this right now. I can't. - I never stopped missing you.
找到我并没那么难
I wasn't that hard to find.
- 所以无论这是在做什么... - 不
- So whatever this is... - No.
- 我之前有个乐队 我们出了一张专辑 - 我知道
- I was in a band. We made an album. - I know.
我在一家画廊开了展览
I had a show at a gallery that was reviewed
《纽约时报》都登了评论
by The New York fucking Times.
我距离你从来都不超过20分钟
I was never more than 20 minutes away from you.
你走路就能找到我
You could have walked.
我有个家庭 我有两个孩子 我之前结婚了 有工作 我...
I had a family. I had two kids. I was married. I had a job. I was--
我就在原地
I was right fucking there.
- 就在你离开我的地方 没有动过 - 在...
- Right where you left me. Right there. - Where--
在我离开你的地方
Where I left you.
我希望你和我一起离开
I wanted you to come with me.
我乞求你和我一起离开 我只是想要保护你
I fucking begged you to come with me. I just wanted to protect you.
我希望我们的父亲保护你
I wanted our father to protect you.
我不知道还能做什么 我如履薄冰
I didn't know what else to do. I was hanging on by a fucking thread.
我必须想办法生存下去 我...
I had to find a way to survive. I didn't--
- 恭喜你啊 小蕾 - 拜托
- Well, congratulations, Reegs... - Please.
你活下来了 你熬出头了
...that you survived. You did it.
拜托
Please.
你什么都不用做
You don't have to do anything.
我爱你
I love you.
我都不认识这些人
I don't even know these people,
但我希望你明白我有多爱你
but I wish you understood how much I love you.
你知道爸爸病了吗
Do you know that Dad is sick?
爸爸
Dad?
你知道他会张开双臂迎接你回家吗
Do you know that he would welcome you back with open fucking arms?
老爸是个懦夫
Daddy is a fucking coward.
你是个懦夫
You are a coward.
你们所有人都是懦夫 好吗
All of you, everyone here is a fucking coward! Okay?
什么 注射毒品就是你所谓的勇气
What, and shooting dope is your idea of bravery?
你最酷了 对吧
You're so fucking cool, aren't you?
听起来我们有许多要讨论的 大家都坐下 先喝点茶
Sounds like there is a lot to discuss. So let's all sit and just have some tea.
你瞧 这就是为什么我回家
You see, this is why I came home.
我记得是这里是我家 所以 感谢你们大家
I remembered it was here. So, thank you all very much.
威廉 你现在可以改变 整个人生 只需要一个决定
William, you can change your whole life right now with just one decision.
求求你 威廉 听听他的话
Please, William, will you just listen to him?
- 求求你 你以后会谢我... - 闭嘴 拜托闭嘴
- I'm begging you. You'll thank me-- - Shut up! Please stop!
别说了 墨瑟
Stop. Mercer.
所以只有我跟着厄尔离开这里 你才肯爱我
So, if I leave with Earl here, it's the only way you'll love me?
我不想要那样的爱
I don't want that kind of love.
不 谢了 我不要那个
No, thank you. I don't want that.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
嘿 托尼 你好吗
Hey, Tony. How you doing?
是这样的 我今晚会和家人一起去阿斯彭
Listen, I'm heading to Aspen with the family tonight.
我可以顺路把文件给你
I could drop the paperwork on the way.
是 谢谢 方便吗 我带着文件呢
Yeah, thank you. Is that gonna work? I got it with me.
好的 行 太好了 好 一会儿见
Okay. All right, great. All right, I'll see you in a bit.
在找东西
Looking for something?
我猜你想要回这文件
I'm guessing you want this back.
我叫小萨
I'm Sam.
- 嗨 小萨 - 嗨
- Hey, Sam. - Hi.
(兰兹曼宿舍)
(纽约大学)
(仅限住户 进入需出示身份证件)
这感觉太不妥了 我们换个地方吧
This is so wrong. Let's go anywhere else.
- 不 - 联合广场有家W酒店
- No. - There's a W in Union Square.
这样有趣多了 11点之后男生禁入
This is way more fun. There are no boys allowed after 11:00.
- 男生  - 对
- Boys? - Yes.
小萨
Sam.
(保护它们的家园 爱熊猫)
好的
Okay.
你室友的熊猫癖让整件事更奇怪了
Your roommate's panda fetish isn't making this any less weird.
她去得梅因度假了
She's in Des Moines for the holidays,
- 所以把焦点放在我身上 别想她 - 好的
- so you can focus on me, not her. - Okay.
你呢 你有什么癖好
What about you? What are you into?
因为看起来你都没在这里住
'Cause it looks like you don't even live here.
我的癖好是你 你知道我住在哪
I'm into you. And you know where I live.
说起来
Speaking of...
怎么
Yeah?
我了解你后 我意识到我其实...
Now that I know you, I realized I don't--
我其实并不真的了解你 一个已婚的金融男
I don't really know you. A married finance guy.
你为什么会闯入我的世界
How did you end up on my doorstep?
有秘密的不只是你
You're not the only one with secrets.
我 我没有秘密
Who, me? I'm an open book.
这是你说过最大的谎了 瞧瞧你说得多么自然
That's the biggest lie you've told yet. Look how easily it came.
- 告诉我你为谁工作 - 没有谁 我是自雇人士
- Tell me who you work for. - No one. I'm self-employed.
每个人都有顶头上司
Everyone answers to someone.
嗨
Hi. Hey.
我住在那里
That's my door.
是
Right.
来自得梅因的熊猫爱好者
Panda lover from Des Moines.
我是萨曼莎的朋友
I'm a friend of Samantha's.
我只是好奇 不知道你是否知道她最近如何
I was just wondering if you knew how she's doing,
或是最近几天有没有见过她
or if you've seen her in the last couple of days.
对 警察也在好奇
Yeah, the cops wondered that too.
警察来过这里
The cops were here?
我...
I--
嘿 能不能问你...
Hey, can I ask you--
小萨说今年秋季她会升大四
Sam told me she was gonna be a senior this fall.
不 她是去年秋季入学的 她是大一生
No. She started last fall. She's a freshman.
(纽约市警察局 阿里帕尔撒)
嘿 我明天午饭可以 好的
Hey. I can do lunch tomorrow. Okay.
蒂姆 我很感谢你总是支持我
Tim, I appreciate that you've always had my back.
谢谢 我们保持联系 好的 谢谢
Thank you. We'll stay in touch. All right, thank you.
蕾根 和威廉的重聚怎么样
Regan, how did the reunion go with William?
非常短暂 另外 我显然来迟了
It was short-lived. And I see I'm too late.
完全不会 艾莫里赶来 挽救了局面
Not at all. Amory has swooped in and saved the day.
在我们找到合适人选接任你父亲之前 他会担任临时主席
He's interim chair until we can find a suitable replacement for your father.
董事会很满意 船趋向稳定了
The board is very happy. The ship has been steadied.
对 或是被劫持了
Yeah, or hijacked.
你逼迫我父亲退休
I mean, you force my father into retirement
然后首席执行官的职位 就自然而然落到你头上
and then the CEO job just falls right into your lap.
临时的 在我们找到永久替任人选之前
Interim. Until we can find a permanent replacement.
很抱歉你弟弟那边的事不顺利
I'm sorry things didn't go so well with your brother.
但我也需要你 此刻比以往更需要
But I need you too, now more than ever.
我们需要彼此
We need each other.
我们早上见吧
I'll see you in the morning.
是
Yeah.
什么都别说
Don't.
来啊 先知 你在正中央
Come on, Prophet. Front and center.
- 过来 嘿 - 什么
- Come here. Hey. - What?
“Ne cede malis” 意思是 “勿向邪恶屈首”
Ne cede malis. Means "yield not to evil."
这是布朗克斯的座右铭 来吧
It's the motto of the Bronx. Come on.
真美
Fucking beautiful.
查理哥们 怎么了
What's the matter, Charlie man?
我不懂我们在这做什么
I don't understand what we're doing here.
小萨热爱音乐 她不喜欢暴力
Sam loves music. She's not into violence.
- 她不会伤害任何人 - 我们也不会
- She'd never hurt anybody. - And neither would we.
没关系的 查理 那栋楼里没人住
It's okay, Charlie. No one lives in that building.
那为什么
Then why?
小萨也问过同样的问题
Sam asked the same questions you are.
我尽力回答了 我们爱这座城市
I tried my best to answer. We love this city.
我们认为它应该属于音乐人和艺术创造者
We think it should belong to the musicians and the artists.
属于黑人和棕色人种
To the Black and the brown folks.
属于梦想者 瘾君子和诗人
To the dreamers, the junkies, the poets.
但是一些很坏的人 正试图将城市从我们手中夺走 而...
But some very bad people are trying to take that away from us, and...
我们只是在反击
we're just fighting back.
通过放火
By setting it on fire?
嘿 你必须相信我 先知
Hey, you're gonna have to trust me, Prophet.
我们有计划
There's a plan.
为民众守住这座城市的计划
A plan to keep this city for the people
并将那些偷走我们岛屿的混蛋们关进去
and lock up those bastards who are stealing our island.
我们正在建造一个新世界
We're building a new world
而那需要先摧毁旧世界
that requires the destruction of the old one.
而且烧毁东西的感觉妙极了
Also, it feels really fucking good to blow shit up.
- 太美妙了 - 可不是
- So fucking good. - Hell yeah.
我们唱和这有关的歌
We sang songs about it.
如果你问的是“小萨会怎么做 ”
If the question you're asking is, "What would Sam do?"
我觉得大家都知道答案 小萨曾是我们的一份子
I think we all know the answer. Sam was one of us,
如果你反其道而行 你是无法接近真相
and you're not gonna get closer to the truth of what happened to her
查出她发生了什么
running in the other direction.
来吧 查理 加入我们 让小萨看见你的本领
Come on, Charlie. Join us. Show Sam what you're made of.
...国庆日中央公园枪击案
...a person of interest in the July 4th shooting
发现一名嫌疑人
in Central Park has been identified.
(纽约警局公布公园枪击案嫌疑人照片)
Police are looking for a Caucasian male between 15 and 25.
警方在寻找一个15至25岁的白人男性
中等身高 身材苗条 深色头发和眼睛
Medium height, slim build, dark hair and eyes.
如任何人有任何信息
Anyone with information,
请拨打212-111-TIPS联络纽约警局
please call the NYPD at 212-111-TIPS.
公园枪击...
As shootings in the park--
苗条的小孩 浓密的头发
Skinny kid, bushy hair.
就像头上趴了只贵宾狗尸体
Like a poodle died on his head.
他不是个小孩 他是个40岁的人
He wasn't a kid. He was, like, 40.
贵族学院风 打扮干净利落 戴着劳力士表
Preppy, clean-cut, Rolex.
我去把录像带调出来
I'm gonna go pull that tape.
如果不是28号牛仔裤的小孩 那是谁
If it's not the 28 jeans kid, then who the hell is it?
跟我来
Come with me.
- 是 - 嗨
- Yeah. - Hey.
照片里的小孩 他母亲打来了
The kid in the photo, his mother called in.
好 是的 我这就过来
Okay, yeah. I'll head right over.
南汉普顿的夏天 许多美好的回忆
Summers in Southampton. So many good memories.
有些事还是忘记为好
Some things are better left forgotten.
- 来吧 查理 - 来吧 先知
- Come on, Charlie. - Come on, Prophet.
- 你能做到 查理 呼吸 - 来吧
- You can do it, Charlie. Breathe. - Do it.
- 我们相信你 - 加油
- We believe in you. - Come on.
- 别多想 - 来吧 先知
- Don't even think about it. - Come on, Prophet.
扔就是了
Just throw it.
- 我们可以走了 - 走
- We can head out. - Let's go.
对
Yeah.
走吧 查理哥们
Come on, Charlie man.
走啊 查理 快点
Come on, Charlie man! Come on!
(警方戒严线 请勿跨越)
吉斯
Keith?
什么事这么急 不能等到明早再说
So, what was so urgent that it couldn't wait till morning?
这是女孩中枪的地方
This is where the girl was shot.
对 我从派对上看到警察了
Yeah, I saw the police from the party.
你对这个案件有特别的兴趣
You have a special interest in this case?
我只是在想...我是说...
I was just won-- I mean--
我觉得我知道她是谁
I think I know who she is.
我在想不知你是否知道...
And I was wondering if you knew if...
你是否...
if you--
你是否知道...
if you knew about--
吉斯 一个年轻女孩
Keith, what is there to know about a young girl
和一个已婚男人之间有什么隐情  而且后者的好福气
and a married man who owes his good fortune,
更别提他实际的财富 都来自他挚爱妻子的家族
not to mention his actual fortune, to his lovely wife's family?
这样一个男人肯定不会 将公私生活混在一起
Surely such a man wouldn't mix business with that kind of pleasure.
不 那不明智
No. That wouldn't be smart.
那是十足的愚蠢 甚至是危险的
It would be pure stupidity. It would be dangerous even.
天啊 艾莫里
Jesus, Amory.
这里发生的事是因为你吗
What happened here, is it because of you?
拜托 吉斯
Come on, Keith.
我们都知道这里发生的事
We both know that what happened here...
是因为你
is because of you.
字幕翻译:易晗